Sign: August 3, Wednesday
Sign: August 4, Thursday
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことはわかんない。
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau. nanika ga chigau.
これってギセイとは違う。何かが違う。
This is different from sacrificing. Very different.
batsugeemu jan, nante omowanai.
罰ゲームじゃん、なんて思わない。
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
de, nande nanoka wakannai
で、なんでなのかわかんない。
But I'm not really sure what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo,
ちょっと釈然としないけど、
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai, ima daiji da, nantemonjanai.
きみの存在、いま大事だ、なんてもんじゃない。
Your existence is no longer so important anymore.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai.
終わらないことなんてこの世の何処にも無い。
Things that last forever don't exist anywhere in this world.
naku no ha tsurai nja, naino,
泣くのは辛いんじゃ、ないの、
Crying is a very painful thing,
ai no SWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
愛のSWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itaine.
ずっと夢みていたいネ。
How I wish my dreams could continue on and on.
motto yasashiku shitaine.
もっとやさしくしたいね。
I want to be more gentle.
kimi to iraretara, HAPPY.
きみと居られたら、HAPPY。
Just being together with you, I'm happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne.
女の子って強いね。
Girls are strong.
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne.
だけどときどき弱いね。
But at times they are weak
bokura no negai ha, HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
ぼくらの希いは、HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
Our dream is to be happy, happy, happy!
sonna hibi mo HAPPY.
そんな日々もHAPPY。
Those happy days.
JUST WANNA MAKE YOU HAPPY☆
Oh.
Huh?
Saionji-sensei.
You should go sleep for a bit.
I'm fine.
Anyway, I wouldn't be able to wake up if I took a nap.
Let's go out and breathe in some fresh air.
We're taking a short break.
Sure!
Have a safe trip.
Everybody should take a break, too.
Call me on my cellphone if there's anything.
The deadline for the script is tonight.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's so hot.
Your hands are so cold. We've got the A/C set too high.
Men's sweat will dirty the scripts if the air-conditioner is turned off.
I heard that stress can cool you down, as well.
Oh yeah?
That new job you mentioned you wanted to do.
I don't think it's worth sacrificing the quality of our work just to pick up another job.
Ma-chan, your mind and body are not that strong.
Besides, we're doing fine right now.
You don't have to work so hard.
But...
What is it?
My popularity is surging right now, but we can't be too sure about next year.
There are lots of new artists out there.
We may be left behind if we're not careful.
Ma-chan, you're too pessimistic.
This isn't healthy for your body.
Oh, there's ink on your face again.
Geez...
You're still a girl, you know.
I'm not a girl! I'm a manga artist!
I'm going back to work!
I'm sorry for disturbing all of you.
Man, it's so hot...
I don't feel like going to work.
Good morning.
I just called you.
I'm sorry, it's too hot.
Do you feel cooler like this?
Yeah.
Let's prepare the lunch box.
OK.
Hey, come over and help.
Yes~!
Rin's summer vacation has started.
We make our lunch boxes together in the morning.
After that, Rin goes to the student childcare centre.
Let's visit Grandpa's grave this Saturday.
It's going to be the Bon Festival soon.
It's just in time for you-
What?
What is it? You don't want to go?
The Bellflowers haven't bloomed yet.
Looks like it'll take a while more for it to bloom.
Well, let's buy from the florist this time.
Then we'll wait for ours to bloom before we go again.
Of course, Grandpa will surely be happy if you bring along the Bellflower that you planted.
Right? Right? Isn't it?
But Grandpa is most happy when you visit his grave.
That's most important.
I understand.
I probably wouldn't have been so thoughtful of Grandpa if Rin wasn't around.
Rin-chan~! Rin-chan~!
Oh, it's Kouki-kun.
I'll want to do it all over again, now that you moved!
Sorry.
Say, why is your hair so fine?
Dunno.
What's wrong?
Wait for me!
Hey! We're going to be late.
What's he doing, that imp?
Daikichi, how many days more to go?
Cool Evening Bon Odori Event
Let's see... about 10 more days.
I found it!
The skin of a cicada.
Skin?
This is somewhat nostalgic.
There are still many in here.
What! It's disgusting.
Stop shaking it!
We're running late!
Hey! Watch out for cars!
I've been here lots of times.
With Grandpa?
Yeah.
I see, Grandma has already passed away.
Grandpa's grandma?
Nope, it's my grandmother.
My mom is Grandpa and Grandma's child.
And I'm the child of my mom.
Oh, so Aunty is Grandpa's daughter?
But... I'll be sisters with Aunty if that's the case.
I was too careless!
I never intended for the conversation to go in this direction.
This way!
Over here!
Kaga Family Grave
The tomb is wet.
That flower vase...
Masako-san also had it.
What is this?
She didn't even come for the funeral.
Rin! I'll be back very soon.
What?
Wait here for me.
Pull out the weeds!
Yes~!
What should I do?
Speaking of which, she actually came with a guy to visit the grave.
W-Wan!
What are you doing?
Why were you hiding in a place like that?
I even thought you were someone dangerous.
I'm here to visit the grave, only that.
I thought I should at least let you know.
Rin is also here.
In front of Grandpa's grave.
Erm... I...
Erm... I really care for Rin.
Frankly speaking, I don't really feel anything for you.
Your personal reasons are also none of my business.
As long as Rin doesn't want to,
I don't intend to let the two of you meet from now on.
I know that much!
What do you specifically want to say after chasing me?
I'm asking if you want to at least take a peek at Rin.
We'll tidy up the grave later, and leave after lighting the joss sticks.
There's still a lot of time.
Rin is still waiting for me.
Well, do whatever you want!
I'll be doing what I'm supposed to do.
Rin... I'm sorry... for making you wait.
Are you all right?
Ah... I had something to do....
What?
No, I'm sorry.
Did you wait for long?
Not really...
Weren't you lonely?
You're weird.
Why are you so upset?
I'm not weird.
Here.
OK.
Place it over there.
Yes~!
She's no longer a baby now.
Blood ties are so amazing.
That's right.
She looks just like you.
From behind...
She's really cute.
That sense of distance.
It's exactly the same as Souichi-san.
What a relief.
I had a huge shock.
The Bon Festival is approaching; such coincidences really do happen.
She turns seven today.
I see.
Your daughter gave me a shock.
I even thought that guy was your ex-boyfriend.
How can that be?
You can't feel even the existence of any form of intelligence coming from him.
But it'll be hard to say after half a century or so.
Half... century?
From a normal perspective, that guy is likely her boyfriend.
Daikichi, you know?
Well, it's still hard to say.
Daikichi!
I didn't think it would be so easy for people to find a new lover like that.
Hey, Daikichi!
Yes, Ma'am!
Can we go to Grandpa's place?
It's pretty near here.
That place no longer belongs to Grandpa.
There are people living there?
Nope, there aren't any at the moment.
But that house belongs to Uncle.
Which means it belongs to my mom's brother.
The altar is also there.
I see.
Can't be helped then.
I can arrange with Uncle if it's just going into the garden.
Really?
But only the garden.
Yeah, I know the way!
I think I want to accept that job we talked about earlier.
What? You serious?
Are you feeling all right, Ma-chan?
I became independent for the sake of my work.
It's unacceptable if I don't work more.
Haven't you been working all this time?
This is really a lot more compared to others; I'm sure of it.
It's not enough.
I have to work until I forget what I ate last night, that kind of level.
I don't remember that sort of thing in the first place.
If I don't do that, I can't seem to forget... many things.
Almost there!
Kaga
It's the same as before.
But you're totally different now.
It's gone.
The Bellflowers, even the dirt is gone.
The Bellflowers are very important to Grandpa.
I'm sure he didn't want to remove them.
Uncle also knows what kind of flower Grandpa likes.
It's just that when winter arrives, they'll wither.
You won't know whether they'll bloom again when spring comes.
The pebbles, too.
The weeds will grow really quick if they're not filled in this way.
It's really troublesome.
Luckily, I transferred Rin's Golden Osmanthus.
It was rescued.
But it's great we moved Grandpa's Bellflower to our house.
It was saved thanks to this.
That's right.
Change may not be entirely a bad thing.
But the grave forever belongs to Grandpa.
Yeah.
Rin!
Wow~!
Happy birthday.
Sign: Happy Birthday! Rin Kaga
It's chocolate flavour!
Saionji-sensei.
I'm counting on you for the final check.
Are you all right?
I really think we won't make it this time.
I really won't be able to continue drawing if you say such things. Stop it!
Wow~!
You can blow it.
I'll definitely complete it.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Daikichi! The night market is going to close.
No, it won't.
Just like Grandpa.
Kouki-kun is here!
What's up?
Didn't we agree to meet at the shrine?
My mom is too slow.
Why are you not wearing your yukata?
I can't jump if I wear it.
Aren't I incredible?
Where's your mom?
She said she's wearing a yukata, and told me to wait for her at the shrine.
Let's go!
The night market is going to close.
What?
Daikichi! Look out for cars!
I know that.
Slow down! It's hard to run with the Geta.
Geta 下駄 = wooden sandals; a japanese footwear which matches the yukata.
I'll carry you.
No way!
I want to be carried.